We have apprehended a dangerous threat
in one of our very own labs.
Quiet!
We believe that this...
this monstrosity...
is the product
of illegal genetic experimentation.
What deranged lunatic
would create something like this?
I prefer "deranged genius,"
but thank you for the introduction.
Dr. Jumba Jookiba, you were tasked
with safely studying biological threats,
not creating them.
A threat?
Experiment 626 is our federation's
most sophisticated weapon.
626 is unstoppable.
Indestructible.
And smarter than 100 supercomputers.
I don't wanna play anymore!
It's an atrocity!
- Destroy it!
- I can't even look at him.
He should be exiled.
Silence!
He did not ask to be created.
Perhaps, if he is so intelligent,
he has the capacity to reason.
Experiment 626, show us
that there is something inside you
that is good.
So naughty.
Throwing up. Throwing up.
I did not teach him that.
You have made our decision easy.
He is clearly the flawed product
of a deranged mind.
Dr. Jookiba, your lab will be destroyed.
Okay. Just leave me 626.
And 626 exiled.
Oh, come on!
- Bailiff.
- Wait.
No, no, no, no! You can't do that.
No!
Don't get any ideas.
These guns are locked
on your genetic signature.
They're not gonna shoot anyone but you.
Knock it off!
Federation strictly forbids being gross.
Don't make me say it--
Uh-oh.
Where is he?
He's loose on Deck C.
Now heading for the hull.
What?
He's trying to find the police...
cruisers.
He... He took the red one.
Fire at will!
He's in hyperspace.
Where will he exit?
In 12 hours, we project he will collide
with a planet called "E-arth."
That's a planet full of water.
Water increases his molecular density.
He'll become heavy and drown.
So I think we can all say
farewell to 62...
You're kidding.
What a pickle we've got here!
If only there was a brilliant genius
around to help you catch that monster.
You! You're the reason we're in this mess.
And I could get you out of it.
If you release me and give me back my lab.
Nonsense.
We'll simply vaporize the planet.
- Captain.
- Armed and ready, Councilwoman.
Hold it! Hold everything!
Excuse me. Sorry. Excuse me. Pardon me.
You can't destroy the planet!
Aw, man.
Who's this?
Agent Pleakley.
Earth expert at your service.
Howdy.
"Earth expert"?
I'm an expert in that planet's flora,
fauna and fashion.
Yeah, this outfit screams "expert."
Yeah. I'm researching an Earth species
that's half-cow and half-boy.
- It's quite fascinating if you're--
- Yes, marvelous.
What's your point?
Earth is a protected wildlife reserve.
We've been using it to rebuild
the mosquito population.
Crikey. Very well.
Dr. Jookiba, you will travel to Earth
where you will capture the escaped
lab experiment known as 626.
Agent Pleakley,
you will be going with him.
You are deputized to ensure
he follows Federation rules.
What? I don't need a babysitter.
This is all very dangerous,
and it's quite likely you'll die.
Do you accept?
With every heart in my body,
of course I accept!
I'm going to Earth! Hey, everyone!
- If I may, Grand Councilwoman...
- Thank you, thank you.
- Can I hug you?
- No.
- Can I hug--
Sorry. Permission to hug
the Grand Councilwoman?
- That's not going to happen.
- Of course. My apologies.
I do not need supervision.
- You have asked me for help.
- Permission to hug my new partner?
Brilliant. Permission granted.
So what I'm just trying to say is, I--
It would just be better
if I went by myself.
Do not let the Earthlings
discover your mission,
or I will be forced to intervene.
This is a dream vacay.
I have so much packing to do!
Well, well, well, 626.
What hideous, pathetic planet is caught
in your crosshairs?
Let's go snorkeling later.
Yeah, that's a great idea.
I know, right? So cool.
They have the best sandwiches.
Are you supposed to be here?
I'm in town for the convention.
Cool.
You're free! Go, go! Live your lives!
No, no, no! No! Lilo.
Not again.
They deserve to be free!
Lilo! I'm gonna have to
talk to Nani about this.
Sorry! Sorry, sorry. Sorry.
Hey, Jimmy's Luau. Hey, brother.
- Go, go. Hurry.
- Sorry.
Hey. You're gonna be late.
Yeah.
- Where is she? She's always late.
- Has anyone seen Lilo?
Lilo, thank goodness.
I thought you were gonna be on time today.
I had to get a sandwich for Pudge.
Is Pudge a friend in need?
He's a fish. I forgot to tell you that.
So, you're late because you fed
a sandwich to a fish?
Yeah. Pudge controls the weather.
She's so weird.
Lilo, honey, come on.
Get dressed, honey.
Guys, look.
I got a friendship bracelet too.
That's not a friendship bracelet.
Ew, garbage girl puts garbage on her arm.
Girls.
Come on.
You know, silly,
it's not a friendship bracelet
if you don't have any friends.
Girls, girls, girls.
Stand in line. Get ready.
No, no, no.
Okay, not today.
She's not coming.
- Kumu!
- Who's her parents?
Girls, go.
She acts up all the time.
Somebody needs to look after her.
She's always causing trouble.
She's just not a good fit.
Kumu, where is her sister?
That's the real question here.
It's a delicate home situation for Lilo.
She's not a bad kid. She just needs--
I don't know, Kumu. I just don't know.
She disrupts the class
and ruined today's performance.
...I'll be so lonely, baby
Lilo? Can you please open the door?
Read the note!
- I'm sorry I missed your performance.
- Blah, blah.
- Pāpā's truck died.
- Blah, blah. Wow!
That must be so stressful for you.
How about you just leave me alone to die?
No, no, no. Not now, not now.
The social worker is here.
You can pout later, Lilo.
That's not how pouting works.
Lilo, open the door.
I can't hear you. It's really weird.
Open the door or I'm breaking it down!
Hey, what is wrong with you?
Mrs. Kekoa.
Hi. Nice to see you.
Can I help you carry anything in?
I'm okay.
Oh, yeah. Would you mind
if we just-- just used the back?
It's just-- just right in the--
right in the back.
These old houses, right?
You just gotta have the... the touch!
There we go!
Actually, would you mind waiting here
for just a second?
- Yes, of course.
- Okay.
- Hey! Don't touch that.
- No, I don't wanna hear it.
- That's mine.
- Turn it off right now.
So, what can I get you to drink?
Do you have tea?
Course I have...
There's a lot of unpaid bills here, Nani.
How often would you say
you leave your little sister home alone?
What? No. I... No.
Why would I do that? I...
I would never leave my sister alone.
Smoke, Nani!
The alarm! The smoke alarm!
Don't worry.
There's no batteries in there.
Lilo!
We took 'em out because it kept going off.
That's not true.
Say aloha to Mrs. Kekoa.
Aloha, Lilo. How are you?
Is that blood?
Yeah, I've been practicing jumping
out of my window.
Ha! She's kidding.
She's actually been
very well-behaved recently.
Haven't you, right?
Yeah.
I've been more than good, Mrs. Kekoa.
I've been doing very, very great at hula.
Made a ton of new friends there,
and they all think I'm the coolest.
I've been eating a lot of organic stuff.
Sometimes I eat too much.
And I've been eating
five or ten times a day.
Sometimes I eat so much, I...
can't...
breathe.
That's enough imagination
for you, you little weirdie.
Tea's ready.
Okay, pretty sweet.
Okay, Nani, we both know
this didn't go well today.
I can see you're trying,
but you're too smart for me
to beat around the bush here.
I know it hasn't been that long
since your parents passed away,
but my job is to make sure that
Lilo is in a stable environment.
And I can't say that
in good conscience right now.
Listen, I know this is a lot.
You're practically a kid yourself.
- Hey, what happened to knocking?
- We decided it was a surf day!
A surf day?
Look, you seem like
a goal-oriented person.
We have a new director coming
into town next week,
and I would really,
really love to tell him
that you girls have turned a corner.
So, why don't we come up with
some goals to achieve by then?
Yeah, yeah.
All right, here.
Three things.
First, I want this house cleaned,
including laundry,
- and a fully-stocked fridge.
- Perfect.
Second, pay all those bills
I saw in the kitchen.
Yes.
And third, file for health insurance
for you and Lilo.
Got it.
If you do those three things by Friday,
I might be able
to give you some more time.
Thank you.
Okay.
It was Capri Sun, yeah?
- Yeah.
- I figured.
And don't forget the insurance.
Yeah, yeah. You got it.
You're gonna need that health insurance
for when I kill you.
Oh, yeah.
You took out the smoke alarm batteries.
I'll show you "can't breathe." Come here!
- Let go of me!
- Yeah, no.
Okay.
No, no, no.
Why didn't you wait at hula?
Because you weren't there.
Do you want them to split us up?
Because that's what's gonna happen
if we don't get it together.
Hey! Did you just lick me?
Stop pretending you're my mom.
At least I don't tell the social worker
I like jumping out of windows.
Well, it's better than listening to you.
Go to your room!
I'm already in my room!
Hey, Alvin.
There she is, Miss Aloha.
Yeah, not today she's not.
Meeting never go well.
I never liked that government lady anyway.
Why is she always so smiley?
Give me the creeps.
Yeah, well, our future is in her hands.
None of that.
Your future is in your hands.
And you're gonna have a very bright future
'cause of that akamai brain of yours.
What?
Your acceptance letter
to your dream school
magically taken out of your trash
and appearing in your bag
at your place of work?
That's a sign, girl.
Will you stop with this?
That school is the best school
in the whole world
for that bionic magnets.
Bio... Marine biology.
Marine biology.
And they already let you in once,
and they wanted to give you for full ride.
Yeah, I know, but, Tūtū, there's no way.
Lilo needs me here.
You ever ask Lilo what she wants?
She's six, so, no.
Sorry, Tūtū.
Had to catch a few extra ones.
The swell was... Hey, Nani!
What are you doing here?
I live here.
We're neighbors.
Yeah. Yeah, that's... that's good.
The waves was crazy today.
You know, I was like,
"Nani should be here,"
'cause you're always, like,
shredding waves,
and I miss shredding you.
I mean, I miss... I miss
seeing you shred waves, so...
- Yeah.
I've always loved watching you.
- Not to say that I like--
- Well said, David.
- Well.
- So, but, like, when...
when are you gonna go surfing?
Maybe when Lilo turns 18.
Enjoy the surf.
Now, make up with your sister, yeah?
You need anything, you just ask, okay?
We're not just neighbors, you know.
We're ʻohana.
- Yeah, I mean, if you want--
- No, no!
No, David, you've said enough.
No, I don't eat... I don't... Yeah.
Warning. Check engine.
Warning. Guidance not--
Warning. Guidance not functional.
Warning. Guidance not functional. Warning.
Crash imminent. Prepare for impact.
Hey. Think I might've nailed
those kalua sliders you like.
Here.
You don't have to eat it.
Nani, am I bad?
What?
That's what everyone says.
Nobody says that.
Maybe some teachers,
and school security guards.
Look, you're not bad.
You just do bad things sometimes.
Just like me earlier,
when I yelled at you.
We just have to learn from our mistakes.
I shoved Mertle Edmonds today.
I know.
You wanna tell me what happened?
People treat me different.
Baby, they just...
They just don't know what to say.
But you...
you didn't mean what you said,
did you?
No. Of course not.
You're my sister.
And I'll always be here for you. Okay?
You got that?
No more tickle town.
Yes, tickle town. Yes, tickle town.
- Tickle town!
- I don't wanna go!
Will you still be able to visit
when you join the Marines?
It's not the Marines. It's marine biology.
Anyway, it's not gonna happen anymore.
I'm staying right here.
Remember when we put up
those constellations?
The Three Sisters.
That one's you. That's me.
And that one means, "time for bed."
I like you better as a sister than a mom.
Ouch.
A shooting star!
Oh, my gosh. I have to make a wish.
You, out!
- What? Why?
- Out!
You can't be here. It won't come true.
Gravity is increasing.
No, it's not, sister.
I wish a wish upon a star,
even though it's very far.
I hope and pray, hope it might
send me my wish tonight.
All I wish is a friend. A real friend.
Someone who won't tease me.
Someone who won't run away.
Like a best friend.
Send me an angel.
The nicest one you have.
Please.
What does this thing do?
Give me that back!
You're not authorized to touch that.
Why? Does it eject you from the ship?
That'd be nice.
It's connected to his tracking collar.
That's never gonna work.
You might as well give him a mood ring.
That collar tells us exactly
where he is at all times.
And that's why our mission cannot fail.
- Mission failed.
- Oh, no!
You know, I am right so often
I don't even enjoy it anymore.
The novelty has completely worn off.
This is bad. This is bad.
Will you relax? I know his every move.
Yeehaw!
What the hell?
- I saw it over there.
- Where did it go?
How are we gonna find him?
We just have to follow
the path of destruction.
I got him!
It talked to me!
There.
Jumba! No, you can't fly this close!
- Seat belts, please.
- Or else--
The humans will see us.
You're jeopardizing the mission.
- We can't be seen.
- I'm in charge now.
Partners are supposed to share.
It's called "vacation."
Once every solar year, the human migrates
to go see a sunlight
and drink celebratory poison.
What are we doing here?
We've gotta find 626.
We will, after we blend in.
How are we gonna do that?
With these. And this.
It's a Federation-certified
cloning device.
What? Who are we gonna clone?
This is never gonna work.
Just be cool and normal.
They look like a bunch of Slim Jims
with googly eyes.
No, not those two.
Look at their disgusting Popsicle bodies.
Human, what a downgrade.
Look at these two.
They look like best friends just like us.
They're perfect.
I'm so sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
I'm so sorry. Here, I will hold you up.
Apologies. What a nice arm you have.
Okay. Are you guys--
And I thank you.
I feel like I'm walking on chopsticks.
My legs feel a little wobbly.
I know. Don't worry. They're fine.
You watched the video I sent you, right?
The walking video? Yeah, but
I didn't know it was gonna be like this.
One foot in front of the other.
Cool and normal.
- Aloha.
- How are you?
- I'm good. Thank you.
- I would like to check in.
- Okay.
So, how many nights
will you be staying with us?
I don't want to stay with you.
I would like my own room with a door.
Oh, and a hot tube.
I would like a hot tube.
A hot tub?
Yes, that's how you say it...
- down here.
- Okay.
And where are you visiting us from?
- Earth.
We both grew up in Earth.
Earth. Okay, that should be about it.
Marcus, could you help him
with his bags please?
Yes.
What is it?
Gotta be some kind of a dog, right?
What kind of dog has six legs, bro?
Nice. That went better than I expected.
Which part, the falling down?
It was embarrassing.
Hangers.
Humans.
Disgusting.
They're really simple creatures.
Every time an asteroid hits their planet,
they have to start life all over again.
It's quite adorable, actually.
You know what I'd really
like to do while we're here?
Sneeze.
Humans do this thing where
they blast juice out of their nose.
What are you doing?
I'm finding him. We only have 48 hours.
Wait! No! Wait, wait, wait.
Humans have never seen a portal before.
The Grand Councilwoman was very clear
not to draw attention to ourselves!
What about that guy?
Listen, I majored in Earth studies
and minored in human textiles.
- Wow!
- Trust me.
We need to blend in.
Fourth floor, please.
Can you stop that?
Aloha, I'm Stephanie Lum.
Breaking news on a strange situation
last night.
A local tour bus ran over an unidentified
wild animal who terrorized a wedding.
The creature is recovering
at the Nā Mea Ola Animal Rescue.
- More on that at 10:00...
- Bingo.
...and hear from the wedding photographer.
Tūtū, can I go into the animal shelter?
Please, please, please.
Nani lets me do it.
Okay. But no wander.
I'll pick you after I pau shopping, okay?
- Yeah!
- Hey, hey, hey, hey!
If anyone tries anything,
hit 'em in the eyes with this.
Cool!
Okay.
No, no.
Can I pet the dogs again?
- Hi, AJ.
- Okay.
But you know you can't feed the dogs
candy again, right?
Lilo.
But it makes them happy.
It makes them have diarrhea.
Nighty night, 626.
Jumba?
Will you please stay still?
I'm already gonna get an earful
for all these ferns we trampled on.
Not to mention if we actually hurt
any of the humans, then we're really--
- Quiet.
- What?
He's listening out for us.
Who's listening?
How good's his hearing?
That's really good!
Yeah, they're called super ears.
Hey, Bailey.
Look who's back.
What's the matter? Is it bath day today?
Man, the mood in here is very depressing.
Sorry, guys. AJ took all my candy.
Are you guys okay?
The Grand Councilwoman was very clear.
I know. I know the rules.
But I know I could catch him
if I used my blaster.
It's too risky.
The Grand Councilwoman was very clear.
You can't hurt the humans.
This one must've been a good one.
Hi.
Auē, what is that?
A dog, I think.
Looks like some kind of baby bear
that come out of the trash.
I like him. Come here, boy.
Yeah, let's put this one back, Lilo.
- Come here.
- Sweetie.
You know, we do have better dogs.
Like, way better.
Not better than him. He can talk.
Say, "aloha."
- Alo--
- Dogs no can talk.
Dogs can't talk, Lilo.
Nah, we can come back later.
Are you sure you like this one?
Yep.
He's perfect.
Look at that genius.
He's using the mini human as a shield.
Got you.
Wait, you can't shoot!
That's your fault.
What?
An animal? What were you thinking?
- Was it her idea?
- No.
- She just said...
- Did she put you up to this?
You have to be polite.
You're our guest!
- It was my idea.
- What?
Tūtū, are you kidding me?
Why on earth would you...
It's been hard for that girl, no?
Hey, take that off him.
And for you too.
And a pet might bring joy.
Remember, we don't hurt chickens, okay?
Like me and Alvin.
I forgot I'm covering
Maya's shift today at work.
Lilo, I need you two
to keep yourselves busy, okay?
I've gotta clean the house before work.
Are we gonna keep him?
- Just today.
- Yeah!
But we are taking it back
first thing tomorrow morning.
And, hey, I need you
to listen to me, okay?
He is your kuleana, okay?
Your responsibility.
You have to be a big girl
about this. Got it?
We promise.
Special Agent Cobra Bubbles,
there's no sign of a pilot.
No tracks. No trails.
Nothing since the incident.
Who says it walked?
Sir?
Sir, you're not implying
this is extraterrestrial?
Sir,
second team intercepted this
from a nearby dog shelter.
You were right.
I'm sorry.
Sir, what division are you from?
When things fall out of the sky,
you're the public's first line of defense.
I'm the last. Often the only.
I need to find out what kind
of threat we're dealing with.
Okay, just stay put.
I'll be back in a second.
Hey, Mertle, look, I got a new dog.
Oh, no, not Lilo.
That's the weirdest thing.
Just like you.
Hey, give that back!
Give that back! Stop it!
Lilo plays with dolls.
Be careful with her!
Lilo, what is up with your dog?
What is up with you?
Wait for me.
- Why are you doing that? Lilo!
- I don't know. Blame it all on him.
What are you doing?
How long does this thing last anyway?
Isn't that them?
Hurry. Hurry. Hurry.
He'll stop at nothing to get away from us.
He will likely head for a big city
for maximum destruction.
But he's gonna find out real soon,
he's stuck here.
Don't you love being
on an island with no big cities?
It's just miles and miles of water.
Come on. I'm gonna take you
to my favorite spots.
You're gonna love it.
Come on. Come in the water
with me. It's so fun.
It's just water.
Ready? Fetch.
Come on. Animals like water.
So you like trouble, huh?
Come on, boy.
Lilo, we can see you.
You know you shouldn't be here.
Go, go, go.
Get down. Get down from there.
- Oh, my God. Control him.
- I'm trying.
No.
Did he just...
No. Stop.
Did he just--
Great, Lilo. Now I have to stitch that up.
What? What? What? What?
That's his name. Stitch!
Lilo, you can't just do that, okay?
Seriously.
I thought I almost hit something.
I...
I am so, so sorry.
Is... Is... Are...
Are you guys okay? I...
Lilo, lock your door.
Was he dragging another man
across the street?
See you later.
Get over yourself. Just give me a second.
Okay. Come on. Come on.
Let's go. Let's go. Come on.
Why do I have to be at your work?
I'm six.
Because someone got kicked out of hula.
Stay here.
It's so boring here.
And no dogs on the table.
- Why not?
- Because people eat off them.
Nani.
Who cares?
They're already covered with bird poo.
Lilo.
Nani!
Come on.
Stay here.
We don't have time for you
to babysit your little daughter.
No, no, it's fine.
It won't happen again. I promise.
I'll go get the table.
Hey, Lilo. How's it going?
Look, David, I got a dog.
You sure that's a dog?
Yeah.
Hey.
You know, your sister.
Have you noticed she's been
a little, like, tense recently?
Don't worry. She's always like that.
But she said that she likes
your butt and fancy hair.
She told you that?
Nope. But I read her text messages.
Okay.
Stitch?
There you are.
We have to stay at the table.
Stitch.
No.
Stitch, put it down.
Yes.
- You.
- No, no, no.
And then...
No.
I'm gonna give you
to the count of three, Stitch.
One.
Wait!
Hey, get back to work.
Cake! Cake!
- Are you guys staying out of trouble?
- Yeah. Of course.
You hungry, boy?
Stitch?
Stitch!
Fire!
I wish it could've worked out.
Not right now, Stitch.
Here you go.
626, you little scoundrel.
- What a piece of work you are.
- Hello, human. Fellow human.
Hello, hello.
Look, fire.
Look, look, look. We're close.
Wait, it's moving. Come on. Come on.
Let's go. We gotta go.
Look, it's Grand Councilwoman.
- Don't answer that. Not now.
- It's Grand Councilwoman.
Your Majesty.
Aren't you just looking delightful today?
It has been 24 hours.
Have you captured the creature?
Start.
Start traveling, please.
We've captured his attention.
Oh, his attention. Good.
There's no... There's no instruments.
There's nothing here!
And are you enjoying the hotel?
- I'm so glad you asked.
- Go. Go.
I'm obviously being sarcastic.
- Go! Systems go.
- Hey!
Engage.
- Oh, no. Other way.
- What you guys think you're doing?
Find the creature.
And remember, you must use discretion.
- Discretion is my middle name.
- Stop this thing.
Oh, brilliant.
Is it too late to vaporize the planet?
- Finger's always on the trigger, ma'am.
- No, no. I'm joking.
What an adorable little psychopath.
You know, you didn't even like that job.
I don't wanna hear it.
And I cleaned the house before work,
so please don't make a mess.
Lilo, he's getting water everywhere.
I'm giving him a bath right now.
Yeah, we're not really equipped
to handle a pet right now and--
We have it down here
that it was a black Lab.
No, I didn't say it was black.
I said it was blue.
- Stitch!
- What's going on in there?
Everything's fine!
Stitch,
you need to listen to me.
No, no, no, Stitch!
Stitch, get back here. We're not done.
Get him back in the bath now.
Where did he go?
There!
Be careful!
Do not go in my clean kitchen.
He's exploring his new house.
That's it.
He's just curious.
Lilo! Help me.
He's a puppy.
It's not a puppy, Lilo.
I'm not even sure it's a dog.
No, no, no.
- Get down.
- Stitch, stop.
Fire.
We are taking it back.
First thing tomorrow morning.
Why are you so strong?
But I wished for him, and he came true.
We said one day. That was our deal.
What does that say? On the 'fridgerator.
We are not keeping this thing.
- "ʻOhana" means family.
- No.
- Family means...
- Dude.
...nobody gets left behind or...
Or forgotten.
Why are you trying to go against
what Māmā and Pāpā said?
Because we were left behind.
Look,
I know all that stuff sounds so nice.
It sounds really nice to me too,
but that is not reality.
This is reality.
And I need you
to start living in it with me.
Look, can you just
get control of your dog?
And I don't even wanna think about
what social services is gonna do.
Agent Foster, get me the social worker.
I'm going undercover.
You've got to stop
causing problems, Stitch.
You can play with Scrump, but be nice.
She was my best friend before you.
Hey, stop it.
Bad dog. Bad dog.
Don't pull on her head.
She's recovering from surgery.
Hey, that's my favorite photo. Stop it.
This is kapu, okay?
That means "off limits."
Don't ever, ever touch this.
Now be good.
Be good for one second.
She was smartest in her whole class.
That's a board.
That's how you surf.
This is how she trained.
She was great at it.
And she has a whole room
"fulled" with trophies.
We used to go to the beach all the time.
She used to be fun.
I wish you could have met her then.
I don't think
you're supposed to drink that.
Did you have a family?
- Family?
- Family.
- That's close.
Like Māmā and Pāpā.
The people at home
who give you lots of hugs and kisses.
And they're there for you, even when...
No.
No family.
Is that why you act bad sometimes?
It's okay.
Maybe my parents talked to your parents
and they sent us to each other.
That's hula.
Hula?
It's a Hawaiian dance.
You wanna try?
Now, follow what I do.
Aloha ʻoe
E ke onaona
Noho i ka lipo
One fond embrace
A hoʻi aʻe au
Until we meet again
I'm so glad I found you.
Can I kiss your nose?
Nani, Nani!
You have to see this.
Okay, just like we practiced.
- What are you doing?
- Watch this.
I'm excited.
Go. I'm watching.
I love that song.
Did you even see?
We're gonna be late.
Come on. Turn that off. Go get your shoes.
That's like a superpower.
- The only superpower that I have is...
- Come on. Let's go.
...sometimes when I run too fast, I fart.
Nice to meet you. I appreciate someone
with your seniority coming to help us.
Well, this is my top priority. Wha--
- Okay, come on.
- Stitch!
- Let's go. Let's go. Hurry.
- Go, go, go!
We're already late. We gotta go.
Mrs. Kekoa.
This is our social services director.
- Hello.
- Hi.
I thought you weren't coming in
until next week.
No, Nani. Your case has been elevated.
So, this is Lilo.
And who is this little friend?
That's my new dog.
Nani, I heard what happened last night.
Can we talk for a second?
Yeah. Sure.
- His name is Stitch.
- Stitch.
If he knew what was happening,
you would lose Lilo right now,
that's all I'm saying.
It shouldn't have happened
in the first place.
- So that was a lot.
- Yeah, and you lost your job.
Hey! What are you doing?
You don't look like a social worker.
I'm a special rank.
Your knuckles say, "Cobra."
- You can read, huh?
- Yeah, I can read.
I'm reading you like a book.
That's how I'll get health insurance.
Don't even worry about it. You said
I had until the end of the week, right?
Lilo, Stitch, let's go find a job.
Gotcha.
But I do want to know
a little bit more about you.
Okay, what would you like
to know about me, Pleakley?
Where'd you get the name Jumba?
It's a family name.
- Are you related--
- There's the truck.
Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
We have to catch him today.
Why did you choose this
foolish method of transportation?
They're eco-friendly.
Let's go. Let's go. Hop to it.
- Okay, this is it, Lilo, okay?
- Let's play Simon Says.
This is our last shot.
If I don't find a job by today...
Simon says wiggle your butt.
...then we are going to be separated.
- Simon says wiggle your legs.
- Hey. Listen.
For real.
I need you and him
to be on your best behavior.
Okay? Yeah?
Okay, wish me luck.
Okay, Stitch, Nani's counting on us.
So let's get to work. Ready? Sit.
Okay, class, listen up.
This is your badness level.
It's unusually high for someone your size.
But we'll fix that.
So, lesson number one.
Lend a helping hand.
Or a paw.
So this is how you clean.
First, use this.
- Okay, we gotta get closer.
- Okay.
That's not...
Lesson number two.
Don't wreck stuff.
It's really fragile, so you can't break it
every time when you--
Now, it's your turn.
You can't just say, "Let's get scooters,"
and that's a plan.
I've been trying to actually be more--
A sneeze!
- Can you tell me how you did it?
- I have no idea. I looked at the light.
Lesson three. Make amends.
There you go.
No. Hey.
No. Hey. Hey.
- Good job, Stitch.
- Yeah, I'm excited.
You know what I mean?
How did it go?
- Not at this hotel.
- Wait. Well...
Nani, Nani, Nani!
Okay.
Maybe you can do something you love.
Go! Go! Go! And pop!
Yeah, Nani!
Yeah!
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hey!
What are you doing?
Why'd you make him so quick?
Get off, Stitch.
- Lilo?
- Nani!
Lilo? Lilo?
...drowning!
- Lifeguard!
- Lilo!
Get off of her!
David, help!
Stitch is pulling her under.
Code 51. I repeat, Code 51.
Send an extraction team now.
Cobra, my hands are tied
until the sample is processed.
Someone's after it too.
The next chance I get, I'm catching him.
You're good. You're good. You're good.
David, help. Help, help, help.
- You got her?
- Okay. David, help, help.
- Lilo, can you hear me?
- Baby.
Up, up, up, up, up, up.
Call an ambulance!
Well, folks.
She asked if she could ride
in the MRI machine.
I told her I would check with you.
She's fine.
She got lucky.
A few more seconds,
it could've been much worse.
But, overall...
Is that a--
It's a service animal.
Okay.
And you can see the front,
and they'll run your insurance.
Okay?
Mahalo.
Uh-oh. What?
No. No. Absolutely not.
It's not just the bills, Nani.
It's time for you to think about
what's best for Lilo.
There's a way that the state will pay
for all of this.
But...
it means that you have to officially
relinquish guardianship of Lilo.
What would that...
look like?
Well, we take our lead from you.
You tell us how you want to proceed.
It's really about making
the transition easier for Lilo.
You'll still get to see her.
It'll just be different.
You can prepare a bag, a few toys,
things that comfort her.
And at that point,
we would leave you some time alone to...
Say goodbye.
No.
We don't say goodbye.
We say a hui hou.
Until we meet again.
I really thought they could make it work.
Why would he protect her like that?
You don't think
they're kind of cute together though?
He's not a pet.
He's an experiment.
And a dangerous one at that.
I just think he's a lot cuter
than you think he is dangerous.
He has sharp teeth. He has claws.
I designed him to be dangerous.
Dangerously cute.
Do not answer that.
Pleakley, don't answer that.
Pleakley. Pleakley.
For me.
Your Majesty. Agent Pleakley here,
not ignoring your call.
We just intercepted
a call from human authorities.
Do you realize what you have done?
- Nope.
- Play the recording.
And take off that ridiculous hat.
Code 51. We found something. Confirm.
And not only have you alerted
the humans to our existence,
but you still haven't captured 626.
Grand Councilwoman, with all due respect,
I'm not sure you know
what's going on with 626.
We have found...
a... a glitch.
Which is making it a little harder
to get him off this planet.
But don't worry.
I'm sure I can figure out...
- We just need--
- A glitch? You're a glitch, you buffoon.
I have had enough, Dr. Jookiba.
You have exhausted my patience.
Consider our deal terminated.
- What?
- No tantrums.
Agent Pleakley is hereby deputized
to detain you under Federation orders
and escort you back to Turo immediately.
Hello?
- Now? Like now?
- No, later. What do you think?
- You cannot do this to my work!
- This is not a debate.
A Federation detail
is on its way to clean up your mess.
Did she hang up?
Jumba?
Yeah, the Federation has always
kind of been that way,
overreacting all the time.
But work's work,
and we gotta follow orders, and...
- What?
- Aloha and mahalo.
You're learning the language--
I really thought we were getting closer.
It's time to do this my way.
Oh, no.
Hey, boo thang.
Hey.
What are you doing, silly?
I'm just playing with my
dolls that I made at Tūtū's.
- Cute.
- Pizza!
So, remember that time that
I went to the North Shore that one summer.
Yeah.
And we were on
opposite sides of the island,
but we could, you know,
go and visit anytime we wanted, right?
We just weren't together all the time.
But we could call.
You would tell me about
all of your fun little adventures
with Alvin and Tūtū and stuff like that.
And we could talk a lot,
just not all the time. You know?
Is this... Is this connecting at all?
You're going back to surf camp?
No. No.
It's just that with Stitch
and everything this week,
things have gone from bad to worse, so...
we're gonna have to make some changes.
And...
You know... I... I have to get some air.
Remember when Pāpā
took us camping out here?
- What?
- Yeah, remember?
I had s'mores. And you also did too.
Pāpā didn't take us camping.
They were fumigating. We had termites.
I went camping. We had fun.
They were really good parents.
Hey.
I changed my mind.
What's that?
I like you as a mom too.
Come on. Do it. For me?
Okay.
Haʻaheo ka ua i nā pali
Ke nihi aʻela i ka nahele
E uhai ana paha i ka liko
Pua ʻāhihi lehua o uka
Aloha ʻoe
E ke onaona noho
I ka lipo
One fond embrace
A hoʻi aʻe au
Until we meet again
I want you to know...
whatever happens, I love you very much.
You ready?
Yeah.
It's gonna be okay.
I promise.
She's not here.
What do you mean, "She's not here"?
I... I don't...
Maybe she's at the neighbor's house.
Go, go, go, go.
What?
Where'd he go?
Stitch?
Stitch!
I thought I lost you.
Stitch break family.
It was a accident. Like a mess-up.
But Stitch...
bad.
Stitch is bad.
You're not bad.
You just do bad things sometimes.
ʻOhana means family.
And sometimes family isn't perfect.
But that doesn't mean they aren't good.
I didn't come here to hurt anybody.
I'm here to help.
This animal belongs to me.
He's not an animal. He's my friend.
Do you have anything else to say?
Hand me that.
You don't know how to use it.
I'm gonna count to three,
and then I want you to drop it.
One...
two...
three!
- Come on!
- Cool.
You're a genius, Stitch.
I made him. I'm the genius.
First rule of stranger danger is:
Find an adult.
Nani!
Nani?
- Lilo!
This is all my fault.
And now I have a wedgie.
Wait. Why would I know
where you sister is?
I don't know. This is
the only phone number I could find.
- Do you wanna order a pepperoni or what?
- Never mind. She's back.
Nani!
Stitch, stop.
Okay, 626, very clever trick.
Funny. I got to stare at my own derriere.
- I've always wanted to do that.
- What are you doing?
Okay, listen. I... I just wanna say...
the Federation doesn't exactly
appreciate what you've done here.
I know you're in there.
Come out, please.
I've got huge plans for you.
I mean, for us.
Go away, hairy potato!
Did you just call me a hairy potato?
That's not nice.
Window, window, window!
Wait! Come back!
Hey! You're gonna run?
You're not gonna run away from all this.
All these memories.
Humans are so attached to each other.
To their things,
to the alien experiments
they've stolen from me.
We gotta go!
"Attachment" means you care.
- Hurry!
- Oh, no.
Lilo! Hurry!
We go now!
And caring causes people
to make very stupid decisions.
Who is "May-May" and "Pay-Pay?"
That's Māmā and Pāpā's room.
That makes a lot more sense.
Stop it, or else.
Or else what?
What are you gonna do?
Yoo-hoo!
There he is.
Aloha!
I'm sorry.
My eye! My eye! My eye!
Why would you do that?
Hey, stop it.
I'm only trying to help!
626, playtime is over.
Okay, okay, okay.
What's the plan, 626?
Say you escape the Federation.
You think you're gonna
just stay here with her?
Live happily ever after on Earth?
You're built to destroy, 626,
and you have.
Look what's happened since you got here.
Her family is falling apart.
Let's just be honest.
The only reason you picked her
at that animal shelter
was for your own protection.
Is that true, Stitch?
See, I don't think that's bad.
I don't think anything you do is bad.
I think it's genius.
If you care about this little girl at all,
you'll leave her here.
Stitch?
This is for the best.
Lilo, run!
David, Nani, meet me back at the house.
You know, you made the right choice.
The Councilwoman was gonna exile you.
She was gonna waste
all my brilliant science.
But I'm gonna do something even better.
And turn you into 627.
- Lilo?
- Lilo!
Lilo!
- Not in here. Okay.
- I'm gonna check the back.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
- Where's Lilo?
She's not here.
Actually, she's on a ship
headed away from the--
Oh, my God! Okay, okay.
That was a really impressive throw.
If we can all...
No, come on. Not that again. I actually...
Agent Cobra Bubbles, CIA.
- What?
- Wait, what? CIA?
Wendell Pleakley
from the United Galactic Federation.
- I'm a fellow government worker.
- What you doing here?
- Yeah, where is my sister?
- Great news.
She's alive and well. Well, actually,
I don't know if she's well.
This only tells me the velocity
of them moving away from the planet.
Enough! I'm taking you out,
and that's that. Let's go.
You know, seeing you
with that little girl made me realize
you're not the heartless monster
I thought you were.
But once I remove your capacity for love,
you'll be perfect.
And then, with 627 by my side,
the Councilwoman won't be able to stop me.
Don't look so sad, 626.
We have each other.
I'm your "o'hannah,"
just like your friend Lisa used to say.
Was that her name, Lisa? Lily?
Limo? Limo... No.
- What was her name?
- Lilo!
Oh, yeah, that was it. Lilo.
Horrible name.
Let's get off this planet, huh?
Initiating hyperspeed.
Ready to launch in two minutes.
You need to tell me what is going on.
- Where is my sister?
- Not now.
The priority is reporting this incident
and getting this thing into custody.
People need to know
what kind of threat they're under.
I'm not really a threat.
I'm kinda quite harmless actually.
But you shouldn't be that concerned.
This is actually my first mission
in the field, so I wouldn't
- really be that concerned. Okay.
- Wait, wait.
Aren't you supposed to protect us?
I took an oath
to protect the American people.
Hey. What you think we are?
Cobra, you were right.
The lab results are in,
and we've never seen anything like this.
Please.
There is something big at play here.
Have you found any additional evidence?
She's my sister.
He's the only one who can help.
Okay.
Also, I took off your bracelets.
They were uncomfortable.
Yeah, it just comes down
to having a vision.
That's all science is.
- It's the ability...
- Red button.
- ...to see what others can't.
- Push. Go.
And I'm guilty of that.
The Grand Councilwoman, for example...
No. No, no, no.
...she couldn't see the future
if it were standing right in front of her.
I wouldn't say that to her face.
Hey! What are you doing?
Hey, 626, don't touch those wi--
Hey! Do not touch another wire.
- Blah, blah, blah, blah.
- Please.
I mean, it's really frustrating
to have this relationship with you.
I say something, you ignore it.
When we get back,
there's gonna be some real changes.
Not so fast, pizza face.
What the...
Lisa.
Let me guess, you don't know
how to work a spaceship.
You little...
What?
- Why do you have party lights?
- Well, that's none of your business.
Why don't you just admit
that your little friend
is a dangerous, freakish monster?
Also, cute and fluffy!
What?
Hyperspeed. Ready for launch.
Time to go home.
Hey! What are you doing?
No, no, no!
Look, look, look,
I had a pretty bad "o'hannah" growing up.
That's not an excuse.
I just thought, give it a little context--
A hui hou, hairy potato.
Can I just propose that sometimes
we need second chances?
And that's just what I...
Trust me, I know.
Pull up. Pull up.
They're descending quickly.
Can you go any faster?
David, faster.
You're driving like a grandma.
- Jump!
- No!
There's no way! I can't!
Gotta jump.
Safe together.
Yes! Yeah.
My photo!
Lilo!
Nani!
Lilo?
Lilo.
- Lilo!
- Nani! Over here!
- Stitch!
- Over here!
Lilo!
- Are you okay?
- He's still down there!
- No! Lilo, no!
- Stitch is down there!
- He saved me. Let go!
We need to go. Let's go.
- Listen to me. Get on the board.
- We have to go save Stitch!
He's still down there!
- Go save him! Please!
- I'm sorry! I can't.
- I can't.
- Let's go.
- Go get him!
- I need you back.
- David, we need to go.
- We need to go, Lilo.
- We need to get you safe.
- We need to get out of here.
- Please! Go save him!
- No, Lilo.
But what about ʻohana?
What about nobody gets left behind?
Lilo, no!
Come on, buddy.
Yeah. We need something more powerful.
Like what?
Try it again. Try it again.
Come on.
Okay. We try that.
Come on. Come on.
- Everybody back! Back up.
- Lilo, get out of the way!
Stitch.
We did all that we could.
We were supposed to grow up together.
I am sorry, baby. I'm so sorry.
Lilo?
Stitch!
The dog talks?
I love you, Stitch.
Oh, gosh.
Let it... Let it go.
It's the family picture!
Good boy, Stitch.
Okay. We're gonna wash that after, yeah?
Auē.
It never ends.
Just...
Stay behind me, Lilo.
- Just get back. Get back.
- Don't worry.
They're just scanning
for deadly parasites.
We're here to retrieve
this dangerous experiment.
Soldiers, take 626 into custody.
No! Hey! Leave him alone!
Let him stay!
I'm afraid I can't allow that.
This creature poses a threat
to your species.
We are sorry for what transpired here.
Rest assured those responsible
will be brought to justice.
How dare you treat
a scientific genius like this!
Hey, Grand Councilwoman, can you--
My precious brain.
- As for experiment 62--
- Stitch.
What?
My name Stitch.
Stitch then.
- Will be--
- Can Stitch say goodbye?
Yes.
Thank you.
Come here, Stitch.
We're gonna miss you.
Who are these people?
This is my family.
I found it all on my own.
It's little and broken, but still good.
Yeah.
Still good.
Grand Councilwoman,
can we leave Stitch with his new family?
Absolutely not.
The Council would require supervision.
And who would possibly want to stay
on this dilapidated mosquito farm?
- Me, me. Me! Me!
- Ha!
Ridiculous.
I cannot risk the global panic that
would ensue if this were to become public.
What if it didn't?
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah, yeah, yeah!
He's CIA.
He's very good at keeping secrets.
Our reconnaissance said you were
going to tell your superiors about this.
How could I ever trust you
to keep it a secret?
Your Highness...
you have my word.
You have all shown me
that there is good in this creature.
However, I cannot reverse
the council's decision.
Experiment 626 has been
sentenced to life in exile.
A sentence that will be
henceforth served here on Earth.
Lilo.
I'm so happy.
Permission to hug the Grand Councilwoman?
Still no.
Of course. Yeah.
We will be checking in now and then.
- Let's go home.
- Yeah.
- Come on, Stitch.
Hey, look on the bright side,
there were a lot of good
memories in this house.
Some good. Some bad.
This one's kind of bad. Yeah.
At least you got the wind chimes.
That's crazy.
David?
Read the room.
He is right though.
Nani.
Hey, baby...
I need to talk to you about something.
I know. This doesn't change our agreement.
Well, actually...
Oh, no. What's wrong?
Nothing.
Well, actually, plenty.
Your house is destroyed.
Your dog is an alien.
Our baby about to go to another ʻohana.
But that's what we've been talking about.
What if Lilo came to live with us?
No, Tūtū, that is way too much. That is...
Smiley already said yes.
It is usually a much easier transition
in these foster situations
if the family,
hānai or otherwise, are involved.
I mean...
Tūtū, that would be amazing.
I mean, after we rebuild...
You'd be right next door.
Really?
No.
You're so smart, Nani.
I think you should join the Marines.
Baby, it's marine biology.
No. I...
It's a lot more complicated than that.
But I want you to go.
And plus, that's what Māmā
and Pāpā would like too.
They told me so.
Yeah, but, Lilo...
it's my kuleana to take care of you.
Nobody gets left behind.
It's also your kuleana to make sure
you no leave yourself behind.
Look at what your parents gave you.
A good head on your shoulders.
A sense of place.
Pride. An akamai brain.
A creative spirit.
But most important, you get each other.
ʻOhana.
Use them.
Make us proud.
- Come here.
- I love you.
I love you too.
Nani, maybe college
can teach you how to cook!
Okay, okay. Come on, Smiley.
- Come here.
- Get in here.
Cobra comes by sometimes
to keep an eye on Stitch.
He's a little scary.
I miss that cute face.
- I miss you.
- Yeah? You do?
- Yeah.
- Well, speaking of that...
Hold on one second.
Is that your dorm bed?
How come it has bars on it?
Are you in jail?
That's not good.
Hello?
Nani? Nani? Hello?
Sup, nugget?
I missed you too, Stitch.
Hey, Double-O-Seven,
go check on Lilo before you go.
Doesn't sound like
sleeping in there, Lilo.
Get the gun. Go.
Nice.
It's jammed.
The trigger's not working.
Try again. Hurry up, Nani.
Better not be up learning another one
of those tick tack dances again.
Go, go, go!
Golly, you're getting big.
Good night, sister.
Goony-snissers.